[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- [whistling]
- [吹口哨]
Breakfast is served.
早餐准备好了。
- That's not the way Mom does it.
- 这不是妈妈的做法。
- There's too much milk in mine.
- 我的牛奶太多了。
- And not enough in mine.
- 我的牛奶又不够。
- Mom usually puts fruit in our cereal.
- 妈妈通常会在我们的麦片里放水果。
- [humming cheerfully]
- [愉快地哼唱]
Ba-zoo-wah!
巴-祖-哇！
Whoa.
哇。
There. Just like Mom.
好了，就像妈妈那样。
all: Ugh.
大家：呃。
- Speaking of Mom, when is she coming back from Grandma's?
说到妈妈，她什么时候从奶奶家回来？
- Yeah, it's been weeks.
是啊，已经几个星期了。
- I can't take it anymore. - We're living like animals.
我受不了了。我们简直像野人一样生活。
- Guys, I haven't even left yet.
伙计们，我甚至还没走呢。
But don't worry, I'm only going to be gone for a few days.
别担心，我只离开几天。
- Why can't Grandma just come here? - No! [dish clatters]
为什么奶奶不能来这里？不行！（碗碟碰撞声）
I mean, you already bought your bus ticket.
我是说，你已经买了车票。
[laughs] - I'm just so bummed
（笑）我只是很失望
I'm going to miss Assistant Week at school.
我会想念学校的助理周。
You kids are going to have so much fun learning how the school works.
你们孩子们将会在学习学校运作的过程中玩得很开心。
- Yeah, I got assigned to Principal Tarian.
- 是的，我被分配给了塔里安校长。
He's letting me do all the P.A. announcements.
他让我做所有的广播通知。
"Attention, cereal,
“注意，麦片，
please report to Dawn's mouth."
请向 Dawn 的嘴巴报告。”
- I get to assist Judy, the cafeteria lady.
- 我可以协助 Judy，食堂的女士。
She gave me my own hairnet.
她给了我自己的发网。
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- I'm assisting Mr. Ackerman, my math teacher.
- 我在协助我的数学老师，阿克曼先生。
He's letting me teach class all by myself on Friday.
他让我周五独自教课。
- Oh, honey, that's great.
哦，亲爱的，那太好了。
- I'm not nervous! Why do you think I'm nervous?
我不紧张！你为什么觉得我紧张？
[laughs nervously]
[紧张地笑]
- Well, I've got the coolest job of all.
嗯，我的工作是最酷的。
Check out my cool custodian keyring.
看看我的酷炫清洁工钥匙扣。
[keys jangle]
[钥匙叮当响]
Ow! Ow!
哎哟！哎哟！
[keys jangle again] Ow!
[钥匙再次叮当响] 哎哟！
- Okay, all right, you know what,
好吧，好吧，你知道吗，
I'm just going to help you out with that. [vehicle honks]
我来帮你解决这个问题。 [车辆鸣笛]
- You guys, I'm going to miss you so much.
- 你们，我会非常想念你们的。
Okay, be good. - We love you.
好吧，要乖。 - 我们爱你。
- I love you too.
- 我也爱你们。
- Good-bye, Mama. all: Love you, Mom.
- 再见，妈妈。 大家: 爱你，妈妈。
- Be back in a few days. Ah, love you. Okay. Bye, guys.
- 几天后就回来。啊，爱你。好吧。再见，大家。
- Bye. - Bye Mom. - Let me take a look at this thing. Come on.
- 再见。 - 再见，妈妈。 - 让我看看这个东西。来吧。
- I'm really gonna miss you, Mom.
- 我真的会想念你的，妈妈。
I wish I could go with you.
我希望我能和你一起去。
- Aw, I know, honey, but while I'm gone,
- 哦，我知道，亲爱的，但我不在的时候，
I need somebody to keep an eye on the boys.
我需要有人帮忙看着这些男孩。
- Okay, don't panic.
- 好的，别慌。
All right, panic!
好吧，慌吧！
- Please hurry back. - Mm.
- 请快点回来。 - 嗯。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- ♪ Na na na na na na ♪ - ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
- ♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪ - ♪ 一，二，三，四！ ♪
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- Ooh, uh, Dawn.
- 哦，呃，Dawn。
- See ya.
- 再见。
- I have a question.
- 我有个问题。
- I'd lose the hairnet.
- 我会摘掉发网。
- No, it's a serious question.
- 不，我是在认真问问题。
- I am serious. Lose the hairnet.
- 我是认真的。摘掉发网。
- The hairnet's staying.
- 发网不会摘。
- Sorry. Whatever you need, just say it. I'm here for you.
- 对不起。无论你需要什么，尽管说。我在这里支持你。
- I have feelings for a girl.
- 我对一个女孩有感觉。
- Could you excuse me for one second?
- 你能让我离开一会儿吗？
[cringing] Continue.
[皱眉] 继续。
- How do I tell her I like her?
- 我该怎么告诉她我喜欢她？
- Oh, I really wish I wasn't hearing this...
- 哦，我真的希望我没听到这个...
because girls like mysteries and secrets,
因为女孩子喜欢神秘和秘密，
which is why you're going to be her secret admirer.
这就是为什么你要成为她的秘密仰慕者。
Good talk. Gotta go. - Wait, Dawn.
谈得好，我得走了。 - 等等，Dawn。
Like my hairnet, this is not going away.
就像我的发网，这事儿不会消失。
- Fine, write her a poem. - About what?
- 好吧，给她写首诗。 - 写什么？
- I don't know, like, rhyme stuff,
- 我不知道，比如押韵的东西，
like rainbows and kittens and fuzzy mittens.
比如彩虹、小猫和毛茸茸的手套。
- Yeah, kittens! That'll sweep her off her feet.
- 对，小猫！那会让她心花怒放。
Next time you see me, I could be asking for smooching advice.
下次见到我，我可能就在问接吻的建议了。
[smooches, laughs]
[亲吻，笑]
- [cringes]
- [畏缩]
♪ ♪
Oh. Bear claws.
哦，熊爪。
- Paws off my claws.
- 别碰我的爪子。
Sorry. But seriously, don't touch 'em.
对不起。但说真的，别碰它们。
- Dawn, you're not going to believe...
- 黎明，你不会相信的...
[sneezes]
[打喷嚏]
What happened. [sneezes]
发生了什么。[打喷嚏]
- You caught the world's cutest cold?
- 你得了世界上最可爱的感冒？
- No, I'm allergic to tulips. - Oh.
- 不，我对郁金香过敏。 - 哦。
- But that's not the news. I have a secret admirer.
- 但这不是新闻。我有一个秘密仰慕者。
- Oh, that's a coincidence, because-- - And he wrote me a poem.
- 哦，真是巧合，因为-- - 他给我写了一首诗。
- That's also a coincidence.
- 这也是巧合。
- He said I make him feel like rainbows and kittens
- 他说我让他感觉像彩虹和小猫
all wrapped up in fuzzy mittens.
都被包裹在毛茸茸的手套里。
I don't know who he is, but I can't wait to find out.
我不知道他是谁，但我迫不及待想找出答案。
- Nurse Mae, I bumped my head.
- 梅护士，我撞到头了。
- Aw, first your finger, now your head.
- 哎呀，先是手指，现在又是头。
Come on in.
进来吧。
Let's get you out of that hairnet and put some ice on it.
让我们帮你摘掉发网，然后敷点冰。
- Rainbows and kittens.
- 彩虹和小猫。
- What is happening?
- 发生了什么事？
I need a bear claw.
我需要一个熊爪面包。
[door closes] - Don't even think about it.
别想了。
♪ ♪
- I'm dying to find out who my secret admirer is.
- 我迫不及待想知道我的秘密仰慕者是谁。
- Trust me, you don't want to know.
- 相信我，你不会想知道的。
I mean... [laughs]
我的意思是... [笑]
Isn't the mystery the best part?
不是吗，神秘感才是最好的部分？
I know if it were me, I'd never want to find out.
我知道如果是我，我永远不会想知道。
That way I could stay this happy forever.
那样我就能永远这么开心了。
- I do like a mystery.
我确实喜欢神秘感。
But, nah.
不过，算了。
Mama wants to know.
妈妈想知道。
- Of course you do. Excuse me one sec.
当然你想。稍等一下。
Hey, Dad-- - One sec. Hot soup.
嘿，爸爸——
Here, take these to table two, and remember,
稍等。热汤。
give 'em the puppy dog eyes and you'll get a better tip.
来，把这些送到二号桌，记住，
Off you go.
用小狗般的眼神看他们，你会得到更多小费。
Okay, what do you need?
去吧。
- Your advice. See, Nicky like-likes Mae.
- 你的建议。你看，尼基对梅动心了。
- What? - Exactly!
- 什么？
And I foolishly told him to become her secret admirer
- 就是这样！
because I didn't know it was Mae,
- 我愚蠢地告诉他要成为她的秘密仰慕者
and now Mae's all excited, but if she finds out it's Nicky,
- 因为我当时不知道是梅
she'll get all weirded out and reject him.
- 现在梅很兴奋，但如果她发现是尼基
What do I do?
- 她会变得很奇怪，然后拒绝他。
- Well-- - Do I say something?
- 我该怎么办？
Do I stay out of it? You're right.
- 嗯——
All I have to do is keep Nicky away
- 我要不要说点什么？
from Mae long enough that he'll forget his crush.
让尼基远离梅足够长的时间，让他忘记他的迷恋。
That way, nobody gets rejected, and nobody gets hurt.
这样，没有人被拒绝，也没有人受伤。
Great talk, Dad.
很好的谈话，爸爸。
- Anytime, honey.
随时欢迎，亲爱的。
- Dawn, when I teach class,
唐，当我上课时，
I'm thinking of breaking the ice with a joke.
我想用一个笑话来打破僵局。
How do you like this?
你觉得这个怎么样？
What's a bird's favorite type of math?
鸟儿最喜欢的数学类型是什么？
Owl-gebra. [both laugh]
猫头鹰代数。[两人都笑了]
- That's a hoot. Gotta go.
那真是个笑话。我得走了。
- You don't feel warm.
- 你不觉得热吗？
- Are you sure? Check again.
- 你确定吗？再检查一下。
- Nicky, come with me quick. - Why?
- 尼基，快跟我来。 - 为什么？
- Uh, you're good with cakes, right?
- 呃，你很会做蛋糕，对吧？
- The best.
- 最棒的。
- Dad needs you to change the urinal cakes
- 爸爸需要你更换楼上浴室的尿布蛋糕。
in the upstairs bathroom.
- 英雄的工作永远做不完。
- A hero's work is never done.
- 好了，快点。
[mouthing] All right, come on.
- 嘿，梅。看看这个。
- Hey, Mae. Check this out.
- 哎呀，妈妈！
Ouchie mama!
哎呀妈妈！
- Wow. You Harper boys are so clumsy.
- 哇。你们哈珀家的男孩真是笨手笨脚。
Here, I have a bandage in my backpack.
这里，我背包里有创可贴。
- Ouchie go bye-bye.
- 痛痛飞走。
- You have got to be kidding me!
- 你一定是在开玩笑！
♪ ♪
- ♪ Mangia, mangia, lovin' the pizza, yay ♪
♪ 吃吧，吃吧，爱上披萨，耶 ♪
♪ Tom's doing-a fine while Anne she is away ♪
♪ 汤姆做得很好，安妮不在的时候 ♪
- Dad.
- 爸爸。
I took your advice, and it totally backfired.
我听了你的建议，结果完全适得其反。
Now Dicky has a crush on Mae too.
现在迪基也对梅有意思了。
And now if the truth comes out, all three of them
而且如果真相暴露，他们三个
are going to be disappointed. - Well--
都会失望的。 - 嗯--
- You're right! Who am I kidding?
- 你说得对！我这是在骗谁呢？
The idea of Mae and either Nicky or Dicky is just plain icky!
梅和尼基或迪基在一起的想法简直太糟糕了！
I'm the one with the real problem here.
我才是这里真正有问题的人。
I should take action. - Yeah, you know--
我应该采取行动。 - 是的，你知道--
- You know, that's good!
- 你知道，这很好！
It's not enough to keep them apart.
仅仅让他们分开是不够的。
I have to drive them apart.
我必须把他们彻底分开。
Thanks for your advice, Dad.
谢谢你的建议，爸爸。
You know there's a pizza on the ceiling, right?
你知道天花板上有一块披萨，对吧？
- Actually, there's-- there's three...
- 实际上，有——有三块...
And a lasagna.
还有一块千层面。
- Hey, Dawn, check it out. [keychain rattles]
- 嘿，Dawn，看看这个。
- You know you're doing it the same, right?
- 你知道你做的方式是一样的，对吧？
- Yeah, but now it doesn't hurt...
- 是的，但现在不疼了...
thanks to Mae.
多亏了Mae。
- Oh, that Mae. [laughs]
- 哦，那个Mae。
She sure is full of good advice...
她确实充满了好建议...
and cooties.
还有那些小毛病。
- I don't care about her cooties.
- 我不在乎她的小毛病。
I think... I like her.
我想... 我喜欢她。
I mean, normally when I see a girl, I think,
我的意思是，通常当我看到一个女孩时，我会想，
"Hey. All right."
“嘿。好吧。”
But suddenly, with Mae,
但突然间，对Mae，
I'm like, "Hey. All right."
我就像，“嘿。好吧。”
What do I do?
我该怎么办？
- Okay, trust me. I know Mae.
- 好吧，相信我。我了解Mae。
And if you really want her to like you,
如果你真的想让她喜欢你，
don't tell her you like her.
不要告诉她你喜欢她。
Go the secret admirer route.
走秘密仰慕者的路线。
- Ooh, I always did want to wear one of those hats
- 哦，我一直想戴那种帽子
and command an entire navy.
并指挥整个海军。
- That's an admiral. - Thank you. I think it's a pretty good goal as well.
- 那是海军上将。 - 谢谢你。我觉得这也是个不错的目标。
- That's admirable.
- 那很值得敬佩。
- I already said, "Thank you."
- 我已经说过，“谢谢你。”
- Just don't tell anyone you like Mae, especially Mae.
- 只是不要告诉任何人你喜欢Mae，特别是Mae。
- Then how's she gonna know?
- 那她怎么知道呢？
- Good question.
- 好问题。
[gasps] You're going to give her tulips
[倒抽气] 你要送她郁金香
and give them to her anonymously.
并且匿名送给她。
- Got it. One question--
- 明白了。还有一个问题——
- "Anonymously" means you don't say who did it.
- “匿名”意味着你不说出是谁做的。
♪ ♪
- That's the last of them. [pot clatters]
- 这是最后一批了。[锅碰撞声]
- Big news from Mae. She loved your poem.
- 来自Mae的大新闻。她很喜欢你的诗。
- She did? [pots clatter]
- 真的吗？[锅碰撞声]
That's great!
太好了！
Oh, I can't wait to tell her it was from me.
哦，我等不及要告诉她是我写的了。
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
哇，哇，哇，哇。
You can't tell her yet, or anybody.
你还不能告诉她，也不能告诉任何人。
- Then what's my next move?
那我下一步该怎么做？
- Another poem, and I already wrote it for you.
再写一首诗，我已经为你写好了。
- Hm.
嗯。
I don't know, Dawn.
我不知道，Dawn。
You rhymed "full of cooties" with "doggy doodies."
你把“满是虫子”和“狗狗便便”押韵了。
- Girls love doggy doodies.
女孩们喜欢狗狗便便。
♪ ♪
- Hey, Mae, I'm at your locker. Where are you? Call me back.
嘿，Mae，我在你的储物柜前。你在哪儿？回我电话。
I can't wait to see what's going on with your secret admirer.
我迫不及待想看看你的秘密仰慕者有什么动静。
- Dawn-- - Secret Admiral.
Dawn——
They're a band.
秘密海军上将。
- Don't care. Listen.
他们是个乐队。
Which pointer do you think
不在乎。听着。
I should use for my presentation?
你觉得我应该用哪个指示器来做我的报告？
The classic retractable?
经典的伸缩式？
Here, here, and here.
这里，这里，还有这里。
Or this modern, hip laser pointer?
还是这个现代、时髦的激光指示器？
Yo, check it,
哟，看这个，
what up?
怎么了？
Both effective, but in untrained hands,
两者都很有效，但在未经训练的人手中，
either one could poke an eye out.
任何一个都可能戳伤眼睛。
- I'd go retractable. Old school's the new school.
我会选择伸缩式的。老派就是新潮。
Happy pointing.
祝你指点江山愉快。
- Dawn, you're not going to believe this.
Dawn，你不会相信这个。
My secret admirer gave me the most ridiculous poem.
我的秘密仰慕者给了我一首极其荒唐的诗。
He rhymed "cooties" with "doodies."
他把“cooties”和“doodies”押韵了。
- Oh, Mae, I am so sorry.
哦，Mae，我真为你难过。
- For what?
为什么？
It was ridiculously funny. [laughs]
真是太滑稽了。[笑]
- It was? [laughs]
是吗？[笑]
- He's sweet and has a great sense of humor.
他很可爱，而且很有幽默感。
- He does?
真的吗？
- And...
而且...
he also gave me...
他还给了我...
tulips!
郁金香！
[sneezes] I don't care if I'm allergic.
[打喷嚏]我不在乎我是否过敏。
How... [sneezes] cute is this?
这...[打喷嚏]有多可爱？
My secret admirer is the perfect guy,
我的秘密仰慕者简直是完美的人，
and I can't wait for him to reveal himself.
而且我迫不及待想让他揭露自己的身份。
I'll see you at your house after school to study.
放学后我会去你家一起学习。
- I heard what Mae said.
我听到了Mae说的话。
So after school at the house,
所以放学后在房子里，
I'm gonna reveal I'm her secret admirer.
我要揭露我就是她的秘密仰慕者。
Thanks, Dawn.
谢谢，Dawn。
- No, wait, you really don't want to do...
不，等等，你真的不想这么做...
- I heard what Mae said.
我听到了Mae说的话。
So after school at the house,
所以放学后在房子里，
I'm gonna reveal I'm her secret admirer.
我要揭露我就是她的秘密仰慕者。
Thanks, Dawn.
谢谢，Dawn。
- You really shouldn't-- I mean...
- 你真的不应该——我是说...
[sighs]
[叹气]
- I'm sorry! It was an accident!
- 对不起！这是个意外！
Thanks, Dawn.
谢谢，Dawn。
♪ ♪
[upbeat music]
[欢快音乐]
♪ ♪
- [sneezes]
- [打喷嚏]
- Principal T., can I ask you a question?
- T校长，我可以问您一个问题吗？
- If it's gonna be "Can I call you Principal T.?"
如果问题是“我能叫你T.校长吗？”
the answer is no.
答案是不行。
- If you had a friend coming over to your house,
如果你有一个朋友要来你家，
and you knew if they showed up, it would be a total disaster,
而且你知道如果他们出现，会是一场灾难，
what would you do?
你会怎么做？
- Well, whenever I have a problem,
嗯，每当我有问题时，
I have a bear claw.
我有一只熊爪。
But you don't need fried dough to solve your problems.
但你不需要油炸面团来解决问题。
You just relax,
你只需要放松，
and I am sure the solution will come to you.
我相信解决方案会自己找上门的。
- Ricky!
瑞奇！
Attention, Ricky Harper,
请注意，瑞奇·哈珀，请到校长办公室报到。
please report to the principal's office.
你是叫我到校长办公室吗，因为我从没被叫去过校长办公室。
- Did you just call me to the principal's office,
这是叫坏孩子去的地方，我不是坏孩子，我是好孩子，一定是搞错了。
because I've never been called to the principal's office.
好了，别说了。
This is where the bad kids are called.
是因为眼睛的事吗？因为那孩子自己撞上来的。
I'm not a bad kid. I'm a good kid. There must be some kind of mistake.
事实上，他弄弯了我的手指，如果有人应该生气，那应该是我。
- Okay, stop talking. - Is it the eye thing? Because that kid walked right into it.
不是眼睛的事。
In fact, he bent my pointer, so if anyone should be mad, it should be me.
哦，那就好，因为完全是我的错。
- It is not the eye thing.
你没惹麻烦。
- Oh, good, because it was totally my fault.
哦，太好了，因为那完全是我的错。
- You're not in trouble.
你没惹麻烦。
Look, do you have feelings for Mae?
听着，你对梅有感觉吗？
- Of course not. - Perfect.
当然没有。
Mae's having a really hard time in math, and it would be great
太好了。
if you could go over to her house after school today and help her study.
梅在数学上遇到了很大的困难，如果你今天放学后能去她家帮她学习，那就太好了。
- Mae's not having a hard time in math.
梅在数学上并没有遇到困难。
She's one of my brightest students.
她是我最聪明的学生之一。
- Well, then, maybe she could give you some feedback
那么，也许她可以对你的教案提些反馈。
on your lesson plan.
为什么？你认为我还没准备好教课吗？
- Why? You don't think I'm ready to teach class?
- 为什么？你不认为我已经准备好教课了吗？
- I didn't say-- - Oh, my gosh, you're right! What was I thinking?
- 我没说-- - 哦，天哪，你说得对！我到底在想什么？
I'm gonna make a fool of myself! "Owl-gebra"?
我会让自己出丑的！“猫头鹰代数”？
Who's gonna laugh at an owl joke?
谁会笑一个关于猫头鹰的笑话？
Who? Who?
谁？谁？
[hyperventilating]
[过度换气]
- Breathe into this.
- 对着这个呼吸。
- Okay, Ricky, you'll be fine. Just keep breathing.
- 好的，Ricky，你会没事的。继续呼吸。
- [breathing heavily]
- [沉重呼吸]
- Ricky's really nervous about his lesson plan.
- Ricky 对他的教案真的很紧张。
Do you mind if he comes over to your house after school
你介意他放学后到你家来练习吗？
and practices?
然后一起练习？
- Are you guys talking about me?
- 你们是在说我吗？
[breathing heavily]
[呼吸沉重]
- Of course.
- 当然。
You and I can study another time.
你和我可以改天再学习。
- Um...
嗯...
Have you girls seen a brown bag out here?
你们女孩们有没有看到外面的一个棕色袋子？
It had my lunch in it.
里面有我的午餐。
- No.
- 没有。
- Sounds like a problem a bear claw could fix.
听起来像是熊爪能解决的问题。
♪ ♪
- Perfect.
完美。
Oh, there you are. Is Mae with you?
哦，你在这儿。Mae和你在一起吗？
I just finished her cake.
我刚做完她的蛋糕。
- Yeah...about that.
是啊...关于那件事。
She's...not coming. - What?
她...不来了。
- Yep, she's pretty unreliable.
什么？
If I were a guy, that'd be enough for me
是的，她非常不可靠。
to not like her.
如果我是男生，那足以让我不喜欢她。
- Boy, that is a deal breaker...
哇，那可是个大问题...
for most guys.
对大多数男生来说。
But I ain't most guys.
但我不是大多数男生。
Now hand me my cake carrier.
现在把我的蛋糕盒递给我。
I'm taking this love show on the road.
我要带着这场爱情秀上路了。
- Uh, no!
呃，不行！
You don't want to do that. - Of course I do.
你不想这么做。 - 我当然想。
The only thing that would keep me away from Mae
唯一能让我远离Mae的事情
is if she likes another guy.
就是她喜欢上另一个男生。
- [snaps fingers]
[打响指]
Funny you should mention that.
有意思，你正好提到这个。
Mae likes another guy. - She does?
梅喜欢另一个男生。
- Yup, one minute she's all about her secret admirer,
是吗？
next minute she's doodling "Mrs. Mae Newguy...erson."
嗯，前一分钟她还对她的秘密仰慕者着迷，
He just moved here from Sweden.
下一分钟就在涂鸦“梅·纽盖伊森太太”。
- This is terrible.
他刚从瑞典搬过来。
- Aww.
这太糟糕了。
There'll be others.
哎呀。
- I heard voices. Is Mae here?
还会遇到别人的。
- Yeah, about that.
我听到有声音，梅在吗？
I--I have some bad news.
我...我有一些坏消息。
Mae met another boy.
Mae遇到了另一个男孩。
And he's Swedish.
而且他是瑞典人。
- Yeah, well, he may be sweet-ish,
是啊，他可能有点甜，
but I'm sweet-er.
但我更甜。
- It doesn't matter how sweet you are.
这与你有多甜无关。
She's met another guy.
她遇到了另一个家伙。
I'm sorry. It's over.
我很抱歉。结束了。
- Oh, okay.
哦，好吧。
Guess I'll just go back upstairs and forget about her.
我想我该回到楼上，忘了她。
Or...
或者...
- What "or"? There is no "or"!
- 什么“或者”？没有“或者”！
- I could apply a fresh coat of body spray
- 我可以喷上一层新的身体喷雾
and go fight for her.
然后去争取她。
- Wait! No! I don't really think...
- 等等！不！我真的不认为...
- Dawn, I've decided to fight for her.
- 黎明，我决定去争取她。
- What? No! Fighting is bad!
- 什么？不！打架不好！
- Not when it's for my lady.
- 但如果是为了我的女士就不一样了。
Oh, I'm gonna bring her this cake and win her back.
哦，我要带这个蛋糕去赢回她。
- Uh--but not with that cake, you're not.
- 呃——但不是用那个蛋糕，你不能。
It's totally smudged.
完全糊了。
- Where?
- 哪里？
- Uh...right over here.
- 呃...就在这儿。
I mean, right over here.
我是说，就在这儿。
- [gasps]
- [吸气声]
- Better go back in and fix it.
- 最好回去修一下。
- Hey, Dawn.
- 嘿，Dawn。
- What are you doing here?
- 你在这里做什么？
I mean, hey, what are you doing here?
我是说，嘿，你在这里做什么？
- We couldn't stay at my house.
- 我们不能待在我家。
Ricky's allergic to my cat, Debbie.
Ricky对我的猫Debbie过敏。
- [sighs] Yeah, Debbie.
是啊，Debbie。
- You've got to be kidding me.
你一定是在开玩笑。
Can I have a word with you? [laughs]
我能和你谈一谈吗？
Excuse us.
请原谅我们。
[door slams]
门砰地关上了。
I thought you told me you didn't like Mae.
我以为你告诉过我你不喜欢Mae。
- I didn't, but now I do.
我以前确实不喜欢，但现在我喜欢了。
And it's all because you made me go over there.
这都是因为你让我去那里的缘故。
So thank you.
所以谢谢你。
- Yay me.
我真棒。
[laughs] What happened?
笑什么？发生了什么？
- I can't explain it.
我无法解释。
I was nervous about my presentation,
我对我的演讲感到紧张，
and then she said everything was going to be okay,
然后她说一切都会好起来的，
and suddenly everything was okay.
突然间一切都好了。
I mean, with most girls, I'm like, "Oh, no."
我的意思是，对大多数女孩，我都会想，“哦，不。”
But with Mae, I'm like, "Oh, yes."
但对Mae，我就会想，“哦，是的。”
- Look, I didn't want to have to tell you this,
听着，我不想不得不告诉你这个，
but there's another boy.
但还有另一个男孩。
He's Swedish, and you don't stand a chance.
他是瑞典人，你没机会的。
- Swedish!
瑞典人！
I guess that's that.
我想就这样了。
- [sighs]
（叹气）
- Or...
或者...
- No! - Yes, I'm going to--
不！——是的，我要——
- Fight for her-- yeah, yeah, I know!
争取她——对，对，我知道！
- I gotta ask. Am I coming in the house?
我得问一下。我能进屋吗？
Am I not coming in the house?
我不能进屋吗？
- One second!
等一下！
[door slams]
[门砰地关上]
- Look, if you want Mae to like you,
听着，如果你想让Mae喜欢你，
you've got to play it cool.
你得表现得酷一点。
Don't tell her you like her.
别告诉她你喜欢她。
In fact, don't tell anyone you like her.
实际上，别告诉任何人你喜欢她。
You know what, don't even speak.
你知道吗，干脆连话都别说。
- Got it. I mean...
明白了。我是说...
- [snaps fingers]
[打响指]
Hey. Glad you're here.
嘿。很高兴你在这儿。
You know, let's go grab some smoothies.
你知道吗，我们去喝点 smoothie 吧。
- I'm not in the mood. - Soup, then.
- 我没心情。 - 那喝汤吧。
- But Ricky said he's going to help me with my math homework.
- 但Ricky说他要帮我做数学作业。
- You don't need help with math.
- 你不需要数学帮助。
You're one of his brightest students.
你是他最聪明的学生之一。
What you need is soup.
你需要的是汤。
And you know what today's soup of the day is?
你知道今天的每日汤是什么吗？
What's your favorite soup? - Alphabet?
你最喜欢的汤是什么？ - 字母汤？
- Bingo! Let's go.
- 宾果！走吧。
- But, Dawn. I have to go to the bathroom.
- 但是，Dawn，我得去洗手间。
- Get Sporty has fresh urinal cakes.
- Get Sporty有新鲜的尿布蛋糕。
- But, Dawn, you're not even wearing shoes.
但是，Dawn，你甚至都没穿鞋。
- Okay, fine.
好吧，好吧。
I didn't want to have to tell you this,
我本不想告诉你这个，
but a certain special someone left me a note saying he wanted
但某个特别的人给我留了张纸条，说他想
to meet you at Get Sporty right now.
现在在Get Sporty见你。
- Do you mean... - Oh, yes.
你是说... - 哦，是的。
That special guy is going to be at Get Sporty any minute,
那个特别的人随时会出现在Get Sporty，
waiting for you with a hot bowl of alphabet soup.
带着一碗热腾腾的字母汤等你。
He said he'll "A-B-C you there."
他说他会“A-B-C你到那儿。”
- Really?
真的吗？
Let's go!
我们走吧！
- Well, I certainly have no idea what they were talking about.
- 好吧，我确实不知道他们在说什么。
- Me neither.
- 我也是。
- I don't understand what's going on most of the time.
- 我大部分时间都不明白发生了什么。
- I need to go to Get Sporty
- 我需要去Get Sporty
without them knowing why.
- 不让他们知道为什么。
- I need to go to Get Sporty
- 我需要去Get Sporty
without them knowing why.
- 不让他们知道为什么。
- Alphabet soup? Mae has fancy taste.
- 字母汤？Mae的品味真高雅。
I must have her.
- 我必须得到她。
♪ ♪
- Dawn, you promised. This is so disappointing.
- 黎明，你答应过的。这太让人失望了。
- I'm sorry, Mae.
- 对不起，梅。
I really thought there'd be alphabet soup.
我真的以为会有字母汤。
- I'm not disappointed about the soup.
- 我对汤本身并不失望。
Well, a little.
嗯，有一点。
I just can't believe my secret admirer didn't show up.
我只是无法相信我的秘密仰慕者没有出现。
- Well, maybe he has cold feet.
- 嗯，也许他临阵退缩了。
I know I do...
我知道我也是……
- This isn't funny, Dawn. I'm devastated.
- 这不好笑，黎明。我心碎了。
This has ruined romance for me...
这毁了我的浪漫情怀...
and soup.
还有汤。
- Well, I'm sure he's around here somewhere.
我肯定他就在这附近的某个地方。
I'll go look for him right now.
我现在就去找他。
Hey, Mae. It's me, your secret admirer.
嘿，梅，是我，你的秘密仰慕者。
You are the coolest girl in the world.
你是世界上最酷的女孩。
But my family is moving away.
但我的家人要搬走了。
If life was like alphabet soup...
如果生活像字母汤...
I'd put "U" and "I" together.
我会把“你”和“我”放在一起。
But it ain't.
但事实并非如此。
So I-B-C-N...
所以我是I-B-C-N...
U.
你。
- Dawn, I know it's you.
- Dawn，我知道是你。
- No, it ain't.
- 不，不是我。
I'm a dude.
我是个男的。
This is clearly a dude hat and dude sunglasses.
这明显是男生的帽子和男生的太阳镜。
- But that is not dude nail polish.
- 但那不是男生的指甲油。
- Too much pink?
- 粉色太多了吗？
- Dawn, please, any dum-dum can tell it's you.
- Dawn，拜托，随便哪个傻瓜都能看出是你。
- Hey, fella!
- 嘿，伙计！
Get your dang Swedish hands off her.
把你的瑞典手从她身上拿开。
- I stand corrected.
- 我承认我错了。
- Mae, I'm your secret admirer.
- 梅，我是你的秘密仰慕者。
- No, you're not. I'm her secret admirer.
- 不，你不是。我才是她的秘密仰慕者。
- But wait.
- 但是等等。
I want to be her admirer.
我想成为她的仰慕者。
We'll have no secrets.
我们之间不会有秘密。
- Back off, she's mine. - No, she's mine!
- 退后，她是我的。 - 不，她是我的！
- No, she's mine! [all yelling at once]
- 不，她是我的！ [所有人同时喊叫]
- Dawn, what's going on here?
- 道恩，这里发生了什么？
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
I'm sorry, Mae.
对不起，Mae。
My brothers started to like you--
我的兄弟们开始喜欢你——
- What? Me? Them?
- 什么？我？他们？
[all shouting at once]
[所有人同时喊叫]
- Why?
- 为什么？
- I--I don't know, but I didn't know what to do.
- 我——我不知道，但我不知道该怎么办。
I didn't want you to be disappointed
我不想让你失望
or them to get their feelings hurt.
也不想让他们受伤。
[all shouting at once]
[所有人同时喊叫]
- So the poems and the flowers were from them?
所以那些诗和花是他们送的？
[all shouting at once]
（大家同时喊叫）
- [shudders]
（颤抖）
- With some intentionally bad advice from me.
还有一些我故意给的糟糕建议。
I'm sorry, Mae. I should have just told you the truth.
对不起，Mae。我应该直接告诉你真相的。
Forgive me?
原谅我好吗？
- Of course I do.
当然我会的。
But I don't know if they will.
但我不确定他们会不会。
- Mae is mine!
Mae是我的！
all: Mine first!
我们都是最先的！
- I know. [sighs]
我知道。[叹气]
My mom told me to keep an eye on them, and I completely messed it up.
我妈妈让我看着他们，结果我完全搞砸了。
- Don't worry. Everything will be okay.
别担心。一切都会好起来的。
- Aw, that's what my Mom says.
哎呀，我妈妈也是这么说的。
[gasps]
[惊讶]
That's what my Mom says!
我妈妈也是这么说的！
Wait a minute.
等一下。
- I was nervous about my presentation,
我对我的演讲很紧张，
and then she said everything was going to be okay,
然后她说一切都会好起来的，
and suddenly, everything was okay!
突然间，一切都好了！
- Ouchie go bye-bye.
- 哎呀，痛痛飞走了。
- Nurse Mae, I bumped my head.
- 梅护士，我撞到头了。
[boys shouting]
[男孩们大喊]
- My box of chocolate! - Not anymore!
- 我的巧克力盒！ - 现在不是了！
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
哎哟，哎哟，哎哟，哎哟，哎哟！
- This ends now!
- 现在就结束！
- Guys, stop!
- 伙计们，停下！
You don't like Mae. You just miss Mom.
你不喜欢梅。你只是想念妈妈。
- We don't miss Mom. - That's childish. - What are we, babies?
- 我们不想念妈妈。 - 那太幼稚了。 - 我们是什么，婴儿吗？
- So what's for dinner, Mae?
- 那么晚餐吃什么，梅？
Okay, I see it now.
好吧，我现在明白了。
both: Mm.
两人: 嗯。
- Look, we might not like Mae that way,
- 看，我们可能不是那样喜欢Mae，
but I want to go on record saying we don't miss our Mom.
但我希望记录下来，我们并不想念我们的妈妈。
- Hey, guys, who wants to talk to Mom on video chat?
- 嘿，伙计们，谁想和妈妈视频聊天？
- [gasps]
- [惊讶声]
I mean... I don't want to, but...
我的意思是...我不想，但是...
she probably wants to say hi to us.
她可能想向我们问好。
- Yeah, bet she misses us like crazy.
- 是啊，我打赌她非常想念我们。
- She's so needy.
- 她真是太需要关注了。
Ugh, cooties.
呃，讨厌的细菌。
- Wait, so you told them I had cooties?
- 等等，你告诉他们我有细菌？
- I... yeah, sorry.
- 我... 是的，对不起。
- And they still liked me?
- 他们还喜欢我？
Mama's got game.
妈妈真有魅力。
[whistling]
[吹口哨]
♪ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
- ♪ 耶！ ♪
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ 耶！ ♪